[Applause]
[Music]
what's up guys it's your host hao tran
here the ceo of etc and as always
uh we're here for another episode of
vietnam innovators today we have a
special guest he
is the chief partnership distribution
officer
is that right correct uh his name is
mark chapman
uh he's arrived a little less than a
year ago from hong kong where he's been
based for several years if not longer
than that
working for prudential the life
insurance company from the uk
uh prudential is growing it's one of the
bigger if not the biggest life insurance
company in vietnam
he'll have to clarify for us and we just
want to know
what not only his role and his team is
doing but also what is prudential's
ambitions in vietnam
and why life insurance is this exciting
growing market
in a young country like vietnam so mark
thank you for joining us on the show
here today
we're very privileged to have someone so
senior from this industry that
not a lot of people know about but is
actually quite pervasive in terms of
affecting millions of people's lives so
today that's the objective to really
illustrate and and paint a picture of
what that industry is
thank you again for joining us mark
thank you for having me pleased to be
here thank you
you make me sound so old well my
reputation
yes a little background too you know um
i from what i understand my neighbor
he so my neighbor in the building that i
live in um he he was an old colleague of
yours from what i understand he
i mentioned to him that you were joining
the show and he was like mark can share
you many stories of
insurance what is insurance what does it
mean for life insurance
in the context of asia but also do an
extent
vietnam so i guess by default you do
okay i'll accept that title yes yeah
so mark i mean to set the tone a little
bit um you know
i'd love to kind of hear from you like
why vietnam and why now
but also maybe a bit about your
background of
how you helped launch life insurance as
we know it in asia and what that looked
like
yeah sure so um my my kind of longevity
with the pru
has gone on uh 32 years so i started
when i was five
um then i did 13 years as an agent
in the uk and then the market was
changing
so there was opportunities in asia so
most people would say why would you go
so far when there's an opportunity to
stay in the uk
um so about kind of 18 19 years ago came
out
did a variety of things but basically
focusing around
bank partners so non-agency distribution
and traditionally agency was where i
started and where the growth markets
have been
um so for basically that all the time
i've been in asia
we've looked at working with bank
partners working how we can get the best
out of
their customer base and catering to
those customers needs
so that's evolved it's been a rocky road
but eventually we've got to where we are
now which is a lot of bank partners
sorting out a kind of one-stop shop to
make sure all their customers are looked
after
so in retrospect uh you said you were
working the uk for some time
people were kind of shocked like oh why
would you leave a market like europe
which is developed and higher spending
or potential
to market like asia that's so
underdeveloped or non-existent
so i mean looking back obviously
best of the best decision i ever made
and the other opportunity is you're in a
market that is
uh understood that has a good adaptation
customers understand
to a market where the penetration rate
is really really low
so uh the evolving aging population
uh having an impact the birth rates have
dropped
people are getting older so they're
living longer in that
enjoyment so the longest holiday of your
life your retirement
people are actually not in the best of
health so they're having to look after
themselves as well
um so there's a multiple of facts so
these aren't
predictions these are what they are
predictions because you can see it on
the facts
there's a huge opportunity so for me
it's very important to make sure that
you know both an individual and their
families are covered
in any event so therefore the
opportunities were vast
and you just have to sometimes take a
leap of faith come across which i did
never regretted a day because it's
allowed me to work through several
countries
so for example prudential now has a
footprint in 13 countries in asia
eight in africa so you can just see
where they are that was completely
different when
and i started zero when you started uh
there was a a little bit in uh what
would have been the colonial countries
which would be in
hong kong malaysia singapore and
expanding the legacy of what was
yeah and africa nothing so if you take
that
as a position of where we are today
the footprint the geographical footprint
in the next five to ten years is most
probably going to be completely
different again
so therefore opportunities are vast and
the same principles of protecting
yourself and the ones you love have
never gone away that's excellent so when
you talk about the kinds of people that
can
um enroll in life insurance be be
customers be part of this
um kind of benefit i guess you could say
layer of society that never existed
before
they're also new consumers meaning
they've probably never enrolled in life
insurance before they don't understand
what it is
and so the opportunity to kind of define
that story is still is still there
it sounds like the story itself is
hundreds of years old
how you sell it or you position it it's
most pro the important issue
but but you're absolutely right there's
a lot of people who
don't like in life insurance or it's not
very attractive
people don't go out of their way to go
and buy it well most likely people just
don't understand it that's the best way
to put it
it is so if you look at some of the like
japan for example
the the percentage of population that
have life insurance is very very high
because it's educated at a very young
age so this is
part it's not just about buying
something it's about educating people
for both their financial health and
their wealth
for the longer term actually everybody
most probably has a need
irrespective of their age their needs
change through their life stages
and it's really important that people do
interact
and purposely go out of the way to find
out if what they've already got is
correct
because just because you bought one
insurance policy when you were 18 or 19
doesn't mean it's the right thing for
when you're 20 30 40 or 50.
so a lot of this is just engaging and
get a trusted advisor
that you can put your confidence in and
make sure they look
after you from when you are single when
you don't need much cover
when you're engaged when you're married
when you have your first child your
second child third fourth fifth
then when you change your careers and
your jobs and your incomes change
going through all the way to the
livestock cycle where
you'll be then looking to plan for
retirement
and then it doesn't stop there now
because whereas people
20 30 years ago may enjoy 10 15 years
people are now enjoying 30 possibly 40
years after retirement
so that those needs those plannings
really need to be
thought out if not the options are you
save more while you're
earning or you work longer i don't know
how many people want to work longer than
they have to
um so therefore it's a balance of what
you can do because even if you do get
old you're not too sure if you can still
you're not
if you're capable of working so there's
a lot of scenarios that you have to plan
for
most of it is what-ifs and if you cater
for the what-ifs
in the eventuality is catered for it's
covered let's let's also hear about how
you reach these consumers
um i understand you're the partnerships
distribution officer
chief officer um how does
how does that work in terms of reaching
out to consumers you have agencies you
mentioned
you have partnerships and maybe a couple
other channels
like could you illustrate what those
mean exactly and how they work
so the the current way of describing it
is omnichannel
which means in layman's terms multiple
multiple
reach out so wherever you want online to
offline offline to online
face-to-face uh any way that a customer
prefers that you should have access to
your services
so we have the traditional agency very
entrepreneurial
very very good maybe not their full-time
career but could be focused on majority
of their time
very very good so they go out have a
great relationship build the
relationships
go through friends families etc that's
exactly how i started
then you have other distribution sources
which are through bank partners
so we're lucky enough to have eight
like-minded bank partners here in
vietnam they have a customer base
that also they would like to protect so
we would reach out to a variety of ways
you can come into a branch you can
either have the person who's employed by
the bank
who could cater banking needs and
insurance needs or you could
bump into somebody who is employed by
prudential who would then be able to
cater so you refer to prudential and
move on
we are growing the digital channel so
you'll notice that we have a
interaction so people can do like a
health app called pulse
that allows you to interact for your
health needs and wealth needs that are
ever evolving
um and you can purchase direct through
there so we have other relationships
with other distributors
where you can get an opportunity to buy
an option to protect you or your
your family or anyone else so therefore
that that evolution
is really driven by what customers want
so if you
listen and you understand the the needs
we actually address those needs because
it's customers preferences if we choose
not to it's a bit like the dinosaurs we
just go extinct
so we really have to make sure that with
the population pyramid changing
with people uh being more digitally
innovative
we need to make sure that we interact
with them in the way that they prefer
um if you don't you're basically cutting
out a large percentage of the population
whose needs still aren't being covered
so
the the second part partnerships that
kind of describes what we
know as bank assurance in the in the
industry is that right um
fairly similar or for my current role
yes
but partnerships are actually broader
because you have those with banks
because they're a financial institution
so many many years ago about 20 years
ago it was a conflict of interest why
would you sell a bank
product and insurance because you would
take the money away from the bank
but actually the money would move anyway
so a lot of the banking institutions
decided they'd like to offer a complete
wealth proposition
of which life insurance is part a large
part of that element
so therefore that can grow but also
evolving you'll find
non-bank partnerships so if you look on
the market you have people who are
[Music]
shop supermarkets you'll have people
online
you only have to look at what's
happening in china for the explosion the
app within app
there's a lot of opportunities that are
available there if you have someone's
attention on an app already
you can probably get them to maybe look
at buying something else
i know what i'm like so if i'm looking
at something or something's prompted or
i managed to look at something
as long as it doesn't take too long to
uh to read it
and it's an easy transaction i
personally
would continue with it and in a way it's
it's targeted too like let's say you go
to a supermarket
i mean i don't know if that's a
potential channel but um you know
maybe some consumers are looking for
healthier products or wellness
products and obviously life insurance
that's resonates with that so in a way
it makes sense a lot of it is just large
databases so
to your point yes it does exist it's
called retail assurance or shop
assurance
so there's lots of people that have been
uh tried to to make it work
some have been successful some have been
not so successful but it's about test
and learn
that's that's why they put the lottery
machines next to the cigarettes
on the far side you have everything else
that's healthier so correct yeah and you
usually have to walk through the the
alcohol before you get the healthy
the other way around but yes um so yeah
there's a there's a huge opportunity
and it's just making sure that you can
reach out to that uh that customer
potential
and generally because of the low
penetration rate the saturation in the
business
it's very very difficult uh to make sure
that you you
to you reach out to the right customer
because you have to really reach out
if it's me you have to reach out to me
the right time the right place the right
moment
with the right offer to get me
interested
so the the whole marketing and
distribution has changed
rather than i know you through your mum
your dad your uncle brother or sister
have an introduction he'll look after
you it's a different chance of engaging
with a discussion
and what does that context look like in
the vietnam market you've worked in hong
kong you've worked in the uk
you've been here for almost a year now
and you're managing hundreds if not
thousands of
uh team that's really focused on that
that context
uh maybe paint that picture of what
those efforts look like in the vietnam
sense
yeah i mean they're not anything that's
unique perhaps well
there's there's nothing about
necessarily being unique but there is a
big difference
of being able to implement effectively
and that's the big difference for most
of the the distribution partners the
first is critical which is
if you have a like-minded partner
partner whose strategies are aligned
that's very important because it means
you come together
if you're looking at customer-centric
proposition you're adapting for what
they need today and in the future
and the long-term stability that would
be a critical
factor that would would be underlying
that that relationship
then what you must do is you make sure
that when you come in to
engage with a customer so i i think of
the customer as me
or you or your my parents you need to be
quite real about it
and when you engage with uh with the
customer you need to address
or approach them first of all in a
method that is correct and appropriate
so as long as that is ethical you're
making sure you can cater to their needs
and you can sometimes decide different
age groups
and different life stages need different
requirements
so on that basis you could actually
almost understand what
what the conversation would look like
when you start so
that is important that you start to
focus on people rather than harassing
customers or harassing me
and really just turning me off because
there's nothing worse than my
perspective provide value somehow
before you engage or understanding a
little bit more about you
before i i have that conversation so a
lot of the market is is about
data analytics about understanding the
customers what they want
or with the banks they have a really
great relationship manager network
where they already have years of
experience with what the customer wants
likes
and have already built up this so you
can leverage on that
to make the approach more empathetic and
make sure that people's needs are
addressed
appropriately excellent um
i don't know if you knew but uh before
this podcast what we usually do is put a
teasers out there on our social media
hey we're meeting like x
person from this company uh what do you
guys think
and actually someone from your team uh
had shared you
uh with a picture of you like on a
marathon i think recently
or something physical activity going out
there um
demonstrating life insurance and and
reality um
and we got quite a few feedback we got
some readers that kind of submitted some
questions and we'd love to share a few
with you
please do so we got quite a number but
only two we can play today so we're
gonna have the first one
so dear zoe our producer will thank you
we'll play the first
hi mark what are some career
opportunities for young people in the
life insurance industry
and more specifically the bench
insurance market
yeah there you go well prudential you've
got thousands if not tens of thousands
of employees
um but it's a you know it's kind of
lumped into financial services in a way
i guess partially at least from a young
person's mind
why consider life insurance other than
working at a bank or consultancy
like what's what's exciting about it
it's a very good question
if you are first if you're prepared to
push yourself
like i did take a leap of faith that's
important
the opportunity are basically a
limitless
because when people have money they want
to
put it spend it or put it away so we can
help them with that
when their circumstances aren't as good
they can come back to us and also we can
give them the money
so for me the opportunity why i looked
at it was that
from day one to still today is that
there's still opportunity there's
nothing gone away
in fact the opportunities have got
bigger and bigger so if you're looking
for
one if you need to understand financial
stability for yourself
and for others it's a great start if you
need almost education about those
industries
the biggest ongoing education i am i can
i am still learning now
things uh about what people's needs are
how we need to address them
so the basic principles are there but
even people
that you see who are very wealthy very
affluent sometimes they just earn money
they don't know how to do
the invest the save the donate whatever
they need to do
so we look at that so the role itself
can first of all
individually you can sort yourself out
so you can go on the road to financial
freedom
you can then help your friends and
family that's the first thing so that's
the logical step
but then by taking the logical approach
you have everyone else out there that
you can help
so i believe that if you're looking for
a longer term career with a huge
opportunity
it's already there there's 100 million
people in vietnam
only if you look at the rest of the
population so you've got china 1.3 1.4
million in india
you've got 280 odd million indonesia
just look around the statistics
there is a huge opportunity of people
who are now
well educated getting good salaries
and what are they doing with it so for
me the opportunities even when i retire
there'll be lots more opportunities for
people to look after people like me
or for them moving through so with
prudential we have a unique
dedicated unit for bank assurance so to
focus specifically on bank assurance
that recruits the best people that gives
them the right training development
education
tailor-made to them and will plot their
career path with them
and because of the scope we mentioned
earlier not just about vietnam if you're
looking to get
a career development and looking for
potential opportunities
just by starting the prudential in
vietnam you've got another 12 countries
in asia
eight currently in africa and all the
other opportunities that will come with
that
so from my perspective i i decided i had
to have a leap of faith i had to give it
the best i could do it's been a rocky
road so things have gone well some
things have gone not so well but
whatever i've turned into today is
because of the experiences i've had
so i was prepared to take that gamble
the gamble for me has worked off well
and i believe that if anyone else has
that like-minded
view and they're prepared to put in a
bit of effort be resilient
that also helps because things aren't
always going to go well and more
importantly if you're happy to deliver
like market leading world-class
performance and results the rewards will
come with it so for me
it's a really uh you know what you put
in is what you get out
and that's never changed for all the
years i've been with prudential
excellent yeah career and personal
finance are actually the top
two out of three wellness being the the
other one uh those are the top three
kind of
categories on vietcetra so i'm not
surprised to see that question
i think the second one is along the same
lines here too
zoe we're gonna play the second question
here i think it is but i might be wrong
we'll find
shared what out driven its success to
this skill
yeah let's let's paint the picture for
all those young vietnamese hopefully
listening this podcast
what what has driven prudential to this
level and
maybe you can share about some
initiatives or recent news maybe that
have
illustrates that yeah well it may not
surprise you we never set out to be
number one
um if you set out to be number one
sometimes i think you do things which
are maybe inappropriate
unethical not correct just for money or
just for profit yeah
or for one year and you you can get a
short-term gain and the long-term pain
that follows
so we actually decided to put the the
customer at the forefront of those
decisions
so all of the product development the
marketing so i don't know if you look at
the websites all the
clips the video clips we've got all of
that marketing is meant to
specifically aim at people people who
are genuinely interested in taking the
next step
so we look at that opportunity
and make sure that we address it so
that's the
first step everyone wants
people-to-people relations not
uh people to company people the
corporates although we have our heads in
the phones a lot of the time
um so the important thing was really to
make sure that we can address the the
right needs
and make sure we can we can address what
customers really really want
uh and and if you're led by that that
will get you basically the cause and
effect
so we made sure that we were aligned
with our bank partners that was critical
so if you're going to take success
factors take the top three
your first you need to uh like any
partnership if you go from girlfriend
boyfriend to marriage with kids
you really have to have the stable
foundation and you must want the same
thing for each other
i think what mark's trying to say is if
if you want to find your next boyfriend
girlfriend
credentials the best place to be most
definitely at least come and try
um the second would be uh execution uh
so many people have some great ideas and
there's great innovators out there
but when you look at what they're able
to do never actually gets delivered
is it the playbook for i mean you having
come from the uk
to asia when it was a very nissan
industry
did you bring the whole playbook with
you to some extent or
was it adapted in any way and maybe was
vietnam a similar kind of case for you
the the approach the generic approach is
very similar
but if you take a kind of you know 70
2010 rule
70 of the financial planning and the
common sense things are there
but really the big difference is the 20
and the 10.
so what's available in vietnam what do
the vietnam people want
how do we offer that to them how do we
make it realistic
and relevant to the audience when you
say what is available to them what does
that
what's happening it's the i guess you've
either got a product
a proposition or a package or a
combination of all of those
it's not about selling a product because
the one thing insurance is
we don't sell a cup you don't break it
and replace it
we sell a promise most of that promise
the kind of the moment of truth is when
an individual makes a claim either for
yourself i want some money back or
something
or for someone in your family and at
that moment of truth we have to make
sure that we deliver to you
because that's the expectations we
should basically fulfill that
plus our vietnamese people very high
expectations on those promises um
i think at the moment they're learning
because a lot of people are still going
through that education process of
why did i take this out because you take
it out because a friend recommends it or
friends has it or your neighbor has it
now the detail the level of detail and
because people are becoming more
educated
um becoming wealthier and living longer
they're really making sure this is about
wealth accumulation
wealth preservation and also the legacy
planning a lot of people are now because
they have money that they may not have
had from previous generations
are also passing it down to other
generations so there's a bigger picture
of people wanting to do things and
because a lot of
vietnamese people are coming back from
educating abroad
it's giving people a different mindset
what can i do what shouldn't i do
why isn't available why can't i do
something for it
and that also helps because it brings in
a new
flourish of thought process and
basically people's needs that need to be
looked after
i think that trend will accelerate you
know the last point you might made about
vietnamese coming back to vietnam
that that trend has only accelerated
because of the pandemic
yes um i've noticed so it's been a year
into this and
around this time last year we got a
surge of applications at viet cetera
um as you might know we're bilingual or
vietnamese in english but the vietnamese
site is significantly larger
but the people reading the the
international edition aside from myself
yourself are also the vietnamese who
live abroad they study abroad they want
to keep in touch with vietnam
they could read in both languages and we
just noticed a huge surge
of this actually so i'm 29 now and
all the vietnamese that studied at uni
with me uh vietnamese nationals
um me being vietnamese american so i
don't count but uh the vietnamese
nationals
five or six of them that i knew
personally they're all in the u.s
they have not come back home but the
vietnamese who are now graduating
like in the next in the last two three
four years
they're all here in vietnam now so
there's this while not
significant in terms of like millions of
people uh but
tens of thousands definitely hundreds of
thousands probably i don't know the
exact numbers but
um you know you kind of start uh kind of
there in a way where
um this group is aware of these concepts
that may not be as common
in vietnam but at the same time
companies like peru are investing
heavily into
that overall market awareness so it's
going to be an inflection point i think
you're absolutely right i totally agree
with you and if you need one of those
individuals as a substantial key
influencer
that will make a significant difference
as you can see in the market here as
long as you have somebody
and people buy into it it will continue
to grow
so yes the opportunity is vast so for me
i just think the market itself is
if you can enjoy the ups and the downs
and you can smooth that off
there's a it's a huge opportunity for
anybody but they have to work for it
so that's the reality of it that's
exciting you know um
you know to kind of end on a note here
too mark you mentioned the market is
only
two percent in terms of uh market
penetration i guess you would say
um and that spells so much opportunity
for um
for the companies here and for the
people to to know what life insurance is
all about
um and you know the question i asked
before was how are we gonna get to ten
percent even five percent sounds like
impossible in a way or not possible
nothing is impossible
yeah um and uh you know it's going to be
exciting to see
where where peru plays a role in that
and um it's just the beginning
so uh we're again very grateful that
you've come over to the show
the studio here today and kind of shared
your comments in a very
uh big industry but maybe not so common
for the vietnamese so hopefully we've
shared something today
uh before we do end of the podcast
though mark i'd love for you to make any
comments about
um you know it's been eight nine months
a year in vietnam
what what's been your experience like so
far any
you live in asia for a while so it's no
surprises i guess well i've been coming
to vietnam for about 10 years
so uh to help with the bank partnerships
and grow them
so coming to vietnam is really like
coming home for me
sounds a bit corny but it's not meant to
be um i have a lot of good friends here
i can find myself my way around town
very easily
the thing i didn't expect was for the
first seven months of the role
i don't think myself the team or anyone
had thought i would still be based in
hong kong
oh so i had a kind of a period of seven
months where i was trying to get through
the visa
and because the hong kong government was
locked down getting all the processes so
i actually only arrived in january
gotcha so i did my quarantine and they
came out in three months
yes okay um so uh and i really have to
say
uh vietnam has done an exceptional job
of controlling the pandemic
when i compare my family is in hong kong
so the children went back to school
last week they're off school for the
whole of this week everything's locked
down
uh the ability to move and what has
happened here
is just exemplar i would say um
so it's it's it helps me getting back to
see my family
but actually why i'm here makes life so
more enjoyable so i'm really glad to be
here
excellent well mark um we look forward
to to collaborating with you and
hopefully seeing more for prudential
very soon thank you again for joining
the show
vietnam innovators everybody mark
chapman the chief partnership
distributions officer
thank you again thank you very much
you can find the full audio of this
episode of vietnam innovators
on spotify and apple podcast don't
forget to subscribe and tune in
every tuesday morning to listen to other
innovating stories
of our guest speakers
thanks for listening to another episode
of vietnam innovators
brought to you by our partners
healthtech startup geo health
they're best known for their doctor at
home services but offer much more than
that
if you haven't already check out their
mobile apps on the app store in google
play for more
or drop by for a visit to their new
smart clinic at m plaza in ho chi minh
city